Akshaya Kolay

Email: <u>akshaya.kolay@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>http://bitly.ws/y2Rq</u>

Portfolio: https://github.com/akshayakolay/Portfolio

Mobile: +46-760902908



I am a technical communicator with experience in software documentation and a background in engineering. I love distilling complex technical information that helps bridge the gap between the product and the user. Aim to increase customer satisfaction and brand value of the organization.

Experience

Freelance Technology Content Writer

Oct 2020-Oct 2022

- Pen How-To's, articles for iOS, android apps, cloud technology, and DevOps.
- Review and update blog content to bring relevant and up-to-date information to readers.
- Author SEO driven articles for the blog sites, some of the posts even ranked first on Google and Bing search.
- Sample of work: http://bitly.ws/y2QJ

SR. Marketing Communications Executive | Nitor Infotech

Pune, India Jul 2019-Apr 2020

- Planned and executed documentation for application development team that ensured effective knowledge transfer for new member.
- Collaborated with cross functional team on designing and creating scope document for Helpdesk application.
- Authored POC documents and thought leadership article as a client-facing collateral.

Associate Consultant | Atos

Pune, India Jul 2017- Jun 2019

- As a technical writer for the RPA team, communicated with technical and business SMEs of different domains to determine the goals and objectives of workflows.
- Wrote **25+** requirement gathering, estimation and functional specification documents.
- Created knowledge base from the ground up and incorporated best practices for the same.
- Ensured that the knowledge base of **500+** documents was fully integrated with new and updated content across the team of **52**.



Application Developer | Atos

Mumbai, India Apr 2015- Jun 2017

- Worked as an application developer to design an Android application focused on LAVA mobile (Indian multinational electronics company) field users and back office users. It helped LAVA to keep track of all the records and also interact with each user of LAVA.
- Designed XML Screens as per the user requirements.
- Trained 2 joiners in PHP and backend functionalities.
- Worked under a senior technical writer to draft initial versions of user manual for the LAVA mobile application and HUL (Hindustan Unilever Limited) sales personnel app.

Education

- Post Graduate Diploma in Advance Computing (PG DAC) from CDAC, Pune, India (Aug 14-Feb 15)
- B.E. in Electronics and Telecommunication from Rashtrasant Tukdoji Maharaj Nagpur University, Nagpur, India (Jun 2009-May 2013)

Exposure to Tools

Authoring: Oxygen XML Editor, GitHub Wiki, Microsoft Word, Swagger Hub and Swagger Editor |

CMS: GitHub, Sharepoint

Diagramming: Microsoft Visio, Google Slides | Editing: Snagit | Development: HTML, CSS,

Markdown, YAML and XML **Other**: UiPath, Postman

Skills

Document Development Life Cycle (DDLC) | API Documentation | Topic-Based Authoring | Audience Analysis | Requirement Gathering | Content Review | Editing | Create Diagrams & infographics

Certifications

- Technical Writing: How to write using DITA XML from Udemy.
- Technical Writing: How to write API software documentation from Udemy.